Riyaz Ahmed

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

meesamriyaz@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | AngelList | Portfolio | Admin

SUMMARY

Professional having work experience across diverse sectors ranging from Full-Stack Web development, Content editing, and administrative tasks. Graduated from Middlesex University, London, UK. Continuously striving to support the potential organization towards establishing an impeccable reputation and reaching its potential in terms of products and exceptional service.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Webflow, Figma, Ruby-on-Rails

Back-End: PostgreSQL, Firebase

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

Remote

Student Mentor

Sep 2023

Car rentals

The Rental Cars Frontend is a Full Stack application that serves as the frontend for a rental car appointment booking system.

• Built with: (HTML, CSS, bootstrap, Javascript, and React as frontend, and Rails as backend Web Link: https://supercarsrentals.onrender.com/

Recipe App

A full stack application is a recipe management app built in rails whereby users can post their new recipes, or see recipes of other users, and perform all CRUD operations.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails

Web Link: https://recipe-app-xhk0.onrender.com/

Budget App

A full stack application, where user can manage their budget: has a list of transactions associated with a category, so that they can see how much money they spent and on what. is a recipe management app built in rails whereby users can post their new recipes, or see recipes of other users, and perform all CRUD operations.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails

Web Link: https://budgetapp-3foi.onrender.com/

Blogsphere

BlogSphere is a classic example of a blog website. It will be a fully functional website that will show the list of posts and empower readers to interact with them by adding comments and liking posts.

• Built with: (HTML, CSS, bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails

Web Link: https://blogsphere-online.onrender.com/

CryptoHub

A Single app (SPA) that displays information about all cryptocurrencies using the coinGecko API. It also gives an analytical view of a selected crypto in the form of chart in terms of daily, weekly, and monthly periods.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, MaterialUI, Javascript, and React

Web Link: https://r-ahmed2022.github.io/cryptohub/

Personal Dashboard - Personal Dashboard is a Chrome extension developed entirely in HTML/CSS and Javascript. It features 24-hour data about the top five cryptocurrencies, a personal To-do List, local weather information, and daily inspirational quotes.

• Built with: (HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ES6, Webpack, Node.js)

Web Link: https://r-ahmed2022.github.io/Personal-Dashboard/

E-commerce App — E-Commerce React App built using React-Js , HTML/CSS utilizing localstorage and Rest API

• Built with: (HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React

Web Link: https://r-ahmed2022.github.io/ramozon-commerce/

MICROVERSE Remote
Student Mentor
Jan 2023 – present

• Mentor junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.

WISHUP TECHNOLOGIES

Online Business Manager

• Secured 3 big clients for the company

Delhi, India

Oct, 2021 - Feb, 2022

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Dec 2023 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Part-Time

- Spend 800+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Develop skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow

Middlesex University, London

Sept, 2006 - June, 2008

Msc, Computer Networks and Managemen